A Guide to the Records of the Office of the President, William E. Lavery, 1975-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series XI: 1985
  - Name Change - Virginia Tech, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC) - Council of Presidents, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC) - International Programs, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - National Science Foundation, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 14A)
  - Performing Arts and Communications, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Personnel - Richmond, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Physics Department, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Planning, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Policy Memoranda, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 18A)
    - Study week
    - Revision in policies on continued appointment
    - Slight change in direct pay policy of the continuing education center
    - Change in membership and charge of the computer committee
  - Provost, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Psychology Department, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Purchasing, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Radford Community Hospital, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 21A)
  - Research Division, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Reynolds Homestead Research Center, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - ROTC, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Route 114 Construction, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 24A)
  - Rural Development, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Scholarships and Grants, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Sea Grant, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Secretary of Administration (2 folders), 1985 (Box 16, Folder 28-29)
  - Security, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Shenandoah Life Insurance Company, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 30A)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Speech Material, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Speeches (2 folders), 1985 (Box 16, Folder 34-35)
  - Staff Meetings, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - State Council of Higher Education, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Student Government Association, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Student Letters, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Student Organizations, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Telecommunications, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - TIAA-CREF Optional Retirement Plan, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 41A)
  - Treasurer and Associate Vice President, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Treasurer's Report, January 23, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - University Calendar, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - University Commencement Committee, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 44A)
  - University Dean, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - University Services and Auxiliary Enterprises, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Upward Bound/Talent Search, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Virginia Center for Coal and Energy Research, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Virginia Tech - The Campaign for Excellence, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Virginia Truck and Ornamental Research Station, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 51)
- Series XII: 1986
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1986 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1986 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Accuracy in Academia (3 folders), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Affirmative Action Award, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 3A)
  - Agriculture and Life Sciences, College of (3 folders), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 4-6)
  - Agricultural Economics, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Engineering, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Agronomic Research Foundation, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Aircraft, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Alumni Association - General, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Alumni Association - President, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Alumni Congratulatory Letters, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - American Council on Education, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Animal Science Department, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Applications for Employment, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Architecture and Urban Studies, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges, Secretary-Treasurer, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Attorney General of Virginia, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Basketball, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Bequests, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Biology Department, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Blacksburg (2 folders), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 26-27)
  - Blueprint Committee on Athletics (2 folders), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 29-29A)
  - Budget Division, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Budget Matters (2 folders), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 31-32)
  - Business, College of, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (2 folders), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 34-35)
  - Chemical Energy Department, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Chemistry Department, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Civil Engineering, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Civil Rights, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Coal and Energy Research, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Comley, Roger E. - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Commandant of Cadets, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Exercises, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Identity and Image, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Computer Science Department, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Computing Center, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Corp of Cadets - Revitalization (2 folders), 1986 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Defense Investigative Service, 1986
    - Dr. Charles W. Schiffert, 1986
    - Arthur M. Squires, 1986
  - Council for Advancement and Support of Education, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Council of Higher Education, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Council of Presidents, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Counseling Center, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Developments - General, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Economics Department, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Education, College of, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Electrical Engineering, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Employee Relations, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Engineering, College of, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Engineering Science and Mechanics, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Entomology, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Environmental Studies, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity and Affirmative Action Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Expenditure Research, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Extension - General (2 folders), 1986 (Box 18, Folder 25-26)
  - Extension Dean, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Forestry and Wildlife Resources, School of, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Founders Day, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - General Professional Advisory Committee (GPAC), 1986 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Geological Sciences, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - George Washington University, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Governor of Virginia (2 folders), 1986 (Box 18, Folder 33-34)
  - Office of the Governor - Secretary of Education, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Office of the Governor - Secretary of Human Resources, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Graduate School, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Hahn, T. Marshall Jr., 1986 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - History Department, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Home Economics--FIDER Accreditation Report, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Honor System Review Board, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Information Services, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Institutional Research, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - International Programs, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Lavery Materials for Administrator's Conference, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Legislators - US Congress (2 folders), 1986 (Box 18, Folder 47-48)
  - Library, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Memos to Faculty and Staff, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - General Faculty Meeting, 1986
    - Celebration of Black History Month, 1986
    - Executive Order No. 1 prohibting employment discrimination, 1986
    - 1986 Christmas and New Year's Holiday Schedule, 1986
    - Governor's Commission on Efficiency in Government Suggestion Form for State Employees, 1986
    - Dr. John M. Perry to serve as Interim Provost, 1986
  - NAACP - Virginia, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges - Council of Presidents, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges - International Programs, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges - Marine Division Budget Committee, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Overnite Transportation Company, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Al Payne's Prayers, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Performing Arts and Communications, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Placement Office (2 folders), 1986 (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
  - Policy memoranda, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 8A)
    - Entrance requirements
    - Policy on reduction in force
    - Policy on re-examination for graduating seniors
    - Affiliated research fellows program
    - The freshman rule
  - Office of the President - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Pulaski Furniture Corporation, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Report to the Board of Visitors on Alcohol and Substance Abuse, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - ROTC - Cadet Command, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Saint Albans Psychiatric Hospital, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Six- Year Plan for Program Development 1988-1994, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Submitted to the State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, July 1986
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Speeches, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Student Housing, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Student Organizations, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Student Programs and Services, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Student Union, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - United Fund Campaign, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 21A)
  - University Bookstore, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - University Calendar, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - University Committee for Teaching Excellence, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - University Development, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Vice President for Administration and Operations, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Center for Coal and Energy Research - Annual Report, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Virginia General Assembly - Higher Education Budget, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 27)
- Series XIII: 1987
  - Professorships in Accounting, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 27A)
  - Administrator's Conference, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Admissions and Records, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Affirmative Action Award, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Affirmative Action Program, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Agriculture and Life Sciences, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Alumni Association, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - American Association of Colleges, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1987 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - College of Architecture, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Architecture/Engineering Addition Protest, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - The Association of Virginia Colleges, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Athletic Association - Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Athletic Director Speech, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Biochemistry Building, Naming of, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Biology Department, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Black History Month Celebration, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 42A)
  - Blacksburg, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Budget Matters, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - College of Business, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Capitol Campaign, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Capital Outlay Requests, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Center for Continuing Education, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (2 folders), 1987 (Box 19, Folder 49-50)
  - Chemical Engineering Department, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Chemistry Department, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Civil Engineering, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Committee Minutes, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Exercises, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Cooperative Education Program, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Corps of Cadets, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Council of Presidents, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Counseling Center, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Dairy Science Department, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Department of Education, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Development - Forbes, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Development - General, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Engineering, College of, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Engineering and Buildings, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Electrical Engineering, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - English Department, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Enrollment Statistics, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity/Affirmative Action Committee (2 folders), 1987 (Box 20, Folder 19-20)
  - Executive Bulletins, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Extension - General (4 folders), 1987 (Box 20, Folder 22-25)
  - Faculty Senate, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Football, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Forestry and Wildlife, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Founders Day, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - General Professional Advisory Committee (GPAC), 1987 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Geological Sciences, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Governor of Virginia (2 folders), 1987 (Box 20, Folder 32-33)
  - Governor's Office - Secretary of Education, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Graduate School, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Hahn, T. Marshall Jr. - the Gallagher Report, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - History Department, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Homecoming, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Honor System Review Board, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Housing and Residence Life, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Human Resources, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Information Services, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Institutional Research, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - International Programs (3 folders), 1987 (Box 21, Folder 4-6)
  - Kellogg Foundation, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Lavery, W.E. - Biographical Information, 1975-1987 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Legislators - General Assembly, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Legislators - US Congress, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Letters - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - The Marching Virginians, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Martin Travel, Closing of, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Meterology, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - National Communications Council, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - National Science Foundation, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - NCAA Violations - Faculty Memo (Box 21, Folder 17A)
  - Outstanding Faculty Award Program, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Department of Personnel and Training, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Philosophy and Religion, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Physics Department, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Plan for the Reorganization of Virginia Tech Athletics Presented to the Virginia Tech Board of Visitors, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 21A)
  - Planning, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Department of Planning and Budget, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Policy Memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Moratorium on proposal of changes in university core courses
    - Faculty review committee
    - Change in policy on allowing graduate credit for certain 4000 level courses
    - University core curriculum - clarification for semester calendar
    - Study research leave
    - Addition of faculty senate representative to computer and library committees
    - Enrollment for degree
    - Credit by examination
    - Establishment of university communications network committee
    - Fraternity and sorority semester rush
    - Software copyright
    - Consulting activities for extension faculty
    - Event approval
    - Policy on sexual harrassment
    - Virginia Tech films policy
    - Addition of two student members to traffic committee
  - Political Science Department, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 24A)
  - Presidential Inaugurations, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Provost, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Purchases and Supply Division, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Recommendations, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Registrar, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Research Division, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Resignation Letter to Faculty and Staff, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 30A)
  - Resignation - Letters of Support to Lavery (4 folders), 1987 (Box 21, Folder 31-34)
  - Retirement, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Reynolds Homestead Advisory Committee, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Minnis E. Ridenour, Correspondence with, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Dependents Association, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - ROTC, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - William H. Ruffner Medal, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Rural Development, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Scholarships and Grants, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Sea Grant (2 folders), 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 43-44)
  - Security, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Self-Study, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Southeastern Universities Research Association, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Speeches (2 folders), 1987 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Speech Material (3 folders), 1987 (Box 22, Folder 4-6)
  - Staff Meetings, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - State Council of Higher Education, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - State Education Assistance Authority, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Student Aid Association, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Student Government Association, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Student Housing, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Student Letters, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Student Organizations, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Student Programs and Services, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Student Survey, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 15A)
  - Student Union, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - University Center for Environmental Studies, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - University Distinguished Professors, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - University Libraries, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Upward Bound/Talent Search, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Veterinary Medicine, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Via- Bradley College of Engineering, Naming of, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Vice President for Administration, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Vice President for Development, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Vice President for Finance, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs (2 folders), 1987 (Box 22, Folder 26-27)
  - Virginia Aviation Commission, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Mining and Minerals Resources Research Institute at Virginia Tech, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Virginia Tech Athletic Association - Letters of Support (2 folders), 1987 (Box 22, Folder 30-31)
  - Virginia Tech Athletic Association - Letters of Non-support, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Tech Foundation, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - VPI Facilities, Inc., 1987 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Washington-Dulles Task Force Advisory Committee, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Water Resources Research Center, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Western Region Consortium, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - William Preston Society, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 38)